Today we will talk about Aditya Birla Active One
Plan, this new plan was launched
some time ago, we will talk about the same,
what are the features, what are the eligibility
criteria, who can get this plan
and finally we will talk about the premium.
Before starting the video, I would
like to introduce myself, my
name is Gurleen Kaur Tikku, I am a
certified financial planner and I
make videos for you every week so that your
personal financial life becomes easy and happy
and your insurance buying journey becomes
smooth because the tagline of our company is
also this - Creating a Wealth of
Happiness. Quick reminder before starting the videos,
if you have
not yet subscribed to our channel, do it so that
you get the right information at the
right time. Let's move on to the video, Aditya
Birla Active Health Plan, this new
plan has been launched,
where the biggest unique selling
point is that chronic conditions are
covered from day one, meaning there is no initial waiting
period. If you have taken the policy today, then
your insurance will be covered from day one.  Which chronic conditions are being covered?
Which are those listed chronic conditions?
Diabetes, Hypertension, Asthma,
Hyperlipidemia, COPD, Obesity, if someone has
coronary artery disease or has a stent inserted,
you will still get this policy.
Aditya Bilal Active One Plan and coverage will be available from Day One.
So two variants are available,
Max and Vital. Both have different
features, we will talk about that later.
Also, another unique selling point is that there is
no maximum entry age. You
can enter this policy at any age. Also, there
is a benefit here which is called
Super Credit No Claim Bonus. It
can go up to 500 and once it reaches 500, it will
not reduce from there. So, once given,
given for life time. Let's
talk in detail about this plan.
First, we will talk about the entry age. The
minimum entry age is 18 years. There is no maximum
limit. The
entry age of dependents is 91 days. Maximum 25  The
dependent child can continue for years
in the same policy. You will get
both individual and family floater policies. The
policy tenure is available for one year, two
years and three years. As you know, if
you take a policy of 2 years or 3 years together, then
you are given some discounts and
you will be eligible for those discounts.
Talking about the family definition, two adults and four children
maximum can be covered. The
definition of individual in this policy
is self-legally married spouse, living
partner, son, daughter, brother, sister, so all these can
come in the individual policy and
in the floater, self-legally married spouse and
living partner, dependent children,
parents and parents-in-law, these can be
covered in your family floater. The
base sum assured which is available,
you can take a base sum assured from Rs 5 lakh to Rs 6 crore.
Now let's talk about room eligibility,
so there is no room term capping,
you will get claim on actuals. ICU  There is
no capping on room capping or ICU as well.
Actual claim will be given on the age. Whatever bill
comes will be paid. Road ambulance,
so road ambulance is covered on the age. Actuals
and emergency air ambulance are also
covered on the age. Actuals will be given to you for
your up to some short day care
hospitalization. Day care hospitalization is
where 24-hour
hospitalization is not required, that
is covered in your policy. Up to some short
domicile hospitalization means you have to take
treatment at home in two conditions.
One is that the patient is so critical that he
cannot go to the hospital. Second, if
beds are not available in the hospital, then
claim for domicile hospitalization will also be given.
AYUSH treatment: If there is AYUSH
hospitalization which is
Ayurveda, Unani, Siddha, Homeopathy, its
hospitalization is covered in your policy.
Up to some no claim bonus, so no claim bonus is
not there. This can be called a bonus.
They have used the name Super Credit.
So, as you renew the policy, in a
way, it is a loyalty addition and every year
you are given a bonus.  So in Max,
this bonus of yours is 100% sum assured which will be
given to you every year and maximum
is Rs.500 but the maximum cover will be up to Rs.3 crore.
In Vital, it is Rs.50 sum assured per year and the maximum will be
100% base sum assured and
this is the benefit you will get up to Rs.3 crore.
This is relative to the
claim and is not linked to the claim. Pre and
post hospitalization expenses, 90 days
before going to the hospital and
180 days after that are
covered in your policy on reimbursement basis.
Annual health checkup, annual health checkup is
complimentary in this policy.
You can claim as per the list and it will be done
on cashless basis only. Refill
benefit: Refill is available in the policy for
unlimited number of times. If your base
sum assured gets exhausted, you
can get it refilled again equal to base sum assured
and this is unlimited number of times.  There is
no restriction for any illness.
Claim protect is
inbuilt. Basically, your non-payable items
are covered up to 100% of the sum assured on
all four annexures. So, all the non-payable items
are covered in your policy in Max
Age, Well Age, Vital. Now let's talk about
Chronic Care, which we talked about as the
unique selling point of the US PH product.
This product can be given to those
who have any chronic health conditions
like diabetes, hypertension, asthma,
hyperlipidemia, COPD, obesity or any
heart condition. So, it will be given even in the case
where stenting has already happened. There is
no PD waiting period in Vital. It is
covered from day one.
Premium is charged accordingly for all these chronic conditions. It is a
little higher premium.
And if you want coverage in Max,
you can take it in Max as well. There you will have to
take a rider called Chronic Care,
so that you will get coverage from day one. So, keep in
mind here that there is an initial waiting
period.  There is also no initial waiting period of 30 days as confirmed
by Aditya Billa team.
You will be fully covered from day one. The
policy for chronic conditions
for which you are taking Vital has
inbuilt day
one coverage for chronic conditions. If you want to take it in Max plan, then
you can choose additional rider which is
chronic care.
You will get that policy on that basis. So,
if someone's HbA1c level is high, he has
type 1 or type 2 diabetes, both, or
heart conditions, then this policy is available in that case also. So
you can check. If
you were not getting health insurance due to these things, then you
can try here and see if you are
eligible here and what policy you
can get. OPD is not covered in this plan,
only IPD is covered. So there are some wellness
benefits which are inbuilt in this plan.
One is health assessment. Your health is
assessed and a report is given to you. The
second is health returns. The more active you are, the more
active you are.  You maintain a lifestyle, the number
of steps you walk is the criteria for
burning calories, so on that basis
you are given health returns
which is equal to 100%, so you
can use it in the future and what I
initially talked about, the best
thing here is that there is no maximum entry age, so
if super seniors also want to take this plan, they can
take it, I
am sharing its premium for you as a reference, you
can see,
so this was Aditya Birla
Active One plan from my side, if you feel that
you were looking for these features in the policy, you were
not able to find the policy due to any
conditions or you wanted such features
where you are fully covered, there is high no claim bonus, there is no
maximum major entry, then
accordingly you can consider this policy,
you can do your due diligence and
see, if you want to ask anything regarding this plan, please
share it
in the comment section, if you want to buy the plan or
want to consult our team, then please consult
on the given number and email ID  We
will get back to you and before we go, a quick
reminder, if you haven't subscribed to our channel yet, do so so that you get the
right information at the right time. See you
soon in the next video. Till then,
stay safe and take care. Bye Bye.